Guide to the Cornell University songs and sheet music, 1870-2000.
Cornell University songs and sheet music, 1870-2000.
- Series IV. Miscellaneous Lyric Sheets and Music Related Items
  - Cornell Songs, Various; 7 versions (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Songs include: Alma Mater, Cornell, Don't Send My Boy to Harvard, The Red and the White, Song for Cornell, Song of the Classes, Song of the Classes (Women's Version), Fight for Cornell, Senior Dirge, Cornell Victorious, Give My Regards to Davy, Carnelian and White, Alumni Song, Evening Song, Crew Song, Reunion Song (Women), Loyal Daughters of Cornell, Bustonian Chorus, Poughkeepsie Course,, Eli, March on Cornell!, Whiffenpoof Song, Lord Geoggrey Amherst, Keep the Home Fires Burning, There's a Long Long Trail A'winding, Chiming Bells, The Chimes, In Bohemia Hall, On the Road to Mandalay, Dink a High Ball, Eveline, When You Wore a Tulip, Abdulla Bulbul Ameer, There is a Tavern in the Town, Mandy Lee, Love's Old Sweet Song, Missouri Waltz, Sweet and Low, Steal Away, Nobody Knows, Swing Low! Sweet Chariot!, Old Black Joe, Beside a Belgian Waterfall, Clementine, The Titanic, Silver Dollar, Pack Up Your Troubles in Your Old Kit Bag, Juanita, Smiles, My Wild Irish Rose, Jacob's Ladder, Jeanie With The Light Brown Hair, Alexander's Ragtime Band, Anchors Aweigh, The Caisson Song, The Marines' Hymn, Army Air Corps Song, It's A Long Way To Tipperary, Over There, I Lost My Heart To A Beta, Shortnin' Bread, Oh Susanna, The Man On The Flying Trapeze, Stein Song, Far Away In The South, The Pope, Mermaid, O, Bring The Wagon, Home, John, Good Night, My Love, Auld Lang Syne, 1875, The Chimes, Kindling-wood, Drinking-song, In The Evening By The Moonlight, I Used To Know A Little Yellow Girl, I've Benn Working On The Levee, Bring the Wagon Home, We Meet Again To-night.
  - Cornell Yells, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: Long, Short, Locomotive, Marching Or Double, Siren
  - Church of Seven Doors, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Poem about Sage Chapel.
  - Founder's Hymn, Undated; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    No composer listed.
  - Page 3 and 4 of a song sheet, Undated; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: All Round The World, Cornell and Alumni Song.
  - Songs For The Senior Informal Smokers And Senior Singing, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Published by the Lehigh Valley Railroad.
    Includes: Cornell, Evening Song, Stop, Stop, Stop, By The Light Of The Silvery Moon, Moonlight In Jungle Land, Mary Jones, Bring The Wagon Home John, Come Josephine In My Flying Machine, Song Of The Classes, The Big Red Team, Alma Mater, Cornell Rowing Song, Kiss Me, Down In Louisiana, Top Of The Morning To You, For I Love It, Put Your Arms Around Me, Honey, Crew Song, Come Be My Lindy Jane.
  - Opening of Sage Chapel, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Hymns sung at the June 13, 1875 opening of the chapel.
  - Class Day Songs Seventy-Eight, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: Cornell, song to the Air Dearest Mae, Bull Dog, Smoking Song, Alma Mater, Here's To Old Cornell, Parting Ode by Robert H. Treman, sung to Auld Lang Syne.
  - Calculus Song, May 28, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Lyrics by William Nelson Smith '90. No music, just lyrics. Dedicated to Sophomores in General and Engineers in Particular.
  - Banquet Songs XCI, February 15, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Probably a song book for the Class of 1891. No music, just lyrics. Includes Class Song, Vive 'L Amour, The Pope, Rosalie, Jingle Bells, Solomon Levi, The Chimes, The Owl and the Pussy-Cat, Alma Mater
  - Sage Chapel Dedication Hymn, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    By Susan E. Linn Sage.
    Published after being found in her papers after her death in 1885. reverse has note "Presented to E. F. Curtis by Miss Linn, October 1898.
  - Cornell Songs for Commencement Week 1899, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: America, Cornell, Evening Song, The Chimes, Cornell Rowing Song, Alma Mater.
  - Cornell Songs For Commencement Week, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: Alma Mater, Smoking Song by Judge F. M. Finch, Evening Song, sung to the air Maryland, Cornell, sung to the air Dearest Mae, The Chimes, sung to the air Tramp, Tramp, Tramp, Cornell Rowing Song, America.
  - Cornell songs for Commencement Week 1906, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes: Alma Mater, Smoking song by Judge F. M. Finch, Evening Song, Cornell, The Chimes, Cornell Rowing Song, America
  - Founder's Centenary Hymn in honor of Ezra Cornell, 1807 - January 11 - 1907, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Composed by Burt G. Wilder.
    Second (Alumni) Edition produced by the Cornell -Co-operative society.
  - Cornell Alumni Song, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    No music, lyrics only, on a small card. Arhur H. Crist '90 publisher. Sung to the air I Want To Go Back To Michigan.
  - Cornell Hymn, 1915; 5 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Lyrics by Albert William Smith '78. Music by James T. Quarles.
  - Origins of the Bustonian Chorus, March 22, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Cornell Daily Sun article explaining the origins of the song composed by Roland Franklin Andrews '00.
  - Home In The Pines, 1939; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Lyrics by John D. Guthrie '39. Sung to the air Home on the Range.
    From a Cornell Forestry student.
  - Songs of Cornell band music, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Music sheets for many instruments in the band. Songs include: Alma Mater, March On Cornell, Cornell Victorious, Carnelian And White, Fight For Cornell, The Big Red Team, Evening Song.
  - The Passing of Zinck's, October 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Article and reprint of article by Romeyn Berry discussing the proper way to sing the Zinck's line in Give My Regards to Davy. Also includes information about the Glee Club drinking at Zinck's and other stories about the bar and bar owner.
  - Davy '79 band music, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Music sheets for many instruments in the band.
  - Alma Mater '80 band music, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous band music sheets, ca. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes various instrument parts for the songs Big Red Team, Cornell Victorious, Fight For Cornell, March On, My Old Cornell
  - Exhibit cards, ca. 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)